What did you want to be when you were growing up?
你小时候想成为什么样的人？
A doctor, an engineer - or maybe a footballer or actor?
医生、工程师——抑或是足球运动员、演员？
We all had big plans for our futures and believed there was a dream job waiting for us – one that would pay well and give great job satisfaction.
我们都曾对未来满怀憧憬，相信世上一定有一份理想的工作在等着自己——一份薪资优厚、能带来满满职业成就感的工作。
But how realistic was that?
但这样的想法现实吗？
Today, in the UK at least, young people are being warned that some of their career hopes and dreams don’t match the types of jobs available.
如今，至少在英国，年轻人被提醒，他们的一些职业理想与当下实际存在的岗位并不匹配。
Research by the charity Education and Employers suggests five times as many 17 and 18 year-olds in the UK want to work in art, culture, entertainment and sport than there are jobs.
慈善机构“教育与雇主”开展的研究显示，英国17至18岁的青少年中，希望从事艺术、文化、娱乐和体育行业的人数，是这些领域现有岗位数量的五倍之多。
The glamour and excitement of working in these employment sectors is obviously a draw.
这些行业自带的光鲜亮丽与激情活力，显然极具吸引力。
But those looking for these types of job will be ‘destined for disappointment’. That’s what the report, Disconnected: Career aspirations and jobs in the UK, says.
但这份名为《脱节：英国青少年的职业理想与现实岗位》的报告指出，那些一心想进入这些领域的人“注定会失望”。
Writing about this for the BBC, Katherine Sellgren points out that while young people are keen to work in art, entertainment, culture and sport, the economy is unlikely to need them all.
凯瑟琳·塞尔格伦在为英国广播公司撰写的相关报道中指出，尽管年轻人热衷于投身艺术、娱乐、文化和体育行业，但行业并不需要这么多人。
In the meantime, there is a shortfall of young people wanting to work in careers such as catering and retail.
与此同时，愿意从事餐饮、零售等行业的年轻人却存在缺口。
Previous research about the career aspirations of young people by the Office for National Statistics also found a ‘reality gap’ between their dreams and the sometimes disappointing truth by the time they reached their early to late-20s.
英国国家统计局此前针对年轻人职业理想开展的研究也发现，当这些年轻人步入二十五六岁到二十八九岁的年纪时，他们的梦想与有时略显残酷的现实之间存在着一道“现实差距”。
Apart from those who aimed to go into teaching, fewer than one in 50 were in the jobs they had wanted – such as a doctor, vet, firefighter or actor.
除了那些立志从教的人之外，只有不到五十分之一的人从事了自己儿时向往的职业——比如医生、兽医、消防员或演员。
Most were working as sales assistants, carers or in sales and marketing.
大多数人都在做销售助理、护工，或是从事销售与市场营销相关的工作。
While it’s good to have aspirations, the aims of young people need to be realistic.
心怀理想固然是好事，但年轻人的目标需要贴合现实。
This latest report suggests that children need to be made more aware of a wider variety of occupations at a younger age.
这份最新报告建议，应该让孩子们在更小的年纪就接触到更多元的职业类型。
It also calls for improved careers advice in secondary schools.
报告还呼吁优化中学阶段的职业规划指导。
A spokeswoman for the Department for Work and Pensions told the BBC that “early careers advice can help young people set out on the right path to the job that channels their interests and unlocks their potential.”
英国就业与养老金部的一位发言人告诉英国广播公司：“尽早提供职业规划建议，能帮助年轻人踏上正确的职业道路，找到能发挥自身兴趣、挖掘自身潜力的工作。”